# **RONEL B. MANLUTAC**

Data Analyst | Data Engineer | BI Specialist | CPA



**Portfolio** 



oneng.manlutac19@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/ronelmanlutac-a903a316a/



0981-436-4811



Magsaysay, Guagua, Pampanga

# **ABOUT ME**

Experienced data enthusiast with more than 3 years of industry experience in gathering, organizing, and summarizing various forms of raw data. Creative in coming up with practical answers to a variety of issues and in structuring reliable data sources to support datadriven solutions.

# PERSONAL INFORMATION

Male Sex:

November 19, 1997 Date of Birth:

Age: 26 Civil Status: Married **Nationality:** Filipino

Languages

Spoken: English, Filipino

# **SOFT SKILLS**

- Can communicate; oral/written
- Strong analytical & problem solving skills
- Notable time management
- Results-oriented and trustworthy
- Hard working, organized and on target
- Possesses pleasing personality and has a good working attitude

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Oct 2023 -Jan 2024

**Business Intelligence Engineer** 

Eastvantage Business Solutions, Inc.

Taguig, Philippines

- Work closely with subject matter experts in migration of Tableau dashboards to Power BI
- Provide expertise and knowledge in providing recommendations on best practices in Power BI (data modelling and reporting)
- Help team in providing solutions to technical implementation problems
- Assist technical lead in planning and implementing business intelligence solution

Dec 2022 -

Data Analyst | Data Engineer

Aug 2023 Nimbyx Philippines, Inc.

Taguig, Philippines

- Automate manual preparation of operational and analytical reports that could take days/weeks to complete
- Build dashboard software application for customer
- Integrate data from multiple sources to build enterprise data warehouse
- Build business intelligence solutions to drive stakeholders derive data-driven decisions
- Assist the organization in designing data and software solutions

May 2020 -Nov 2022

Senior Business Intelligence Developer | Data Analyst | Business Analyst (Business Analytics)

**Small Business Corporation** 

Makati, Philippines

- Design and build the enterprise data warehouse and business intelligence solutions
- Lead data analytics team in the development of dashboards
- Assist key management stakeholders in deriving data-driven decisions in managing portfolios and launching new products
- Statutory reports compliance

# **TOOLS AND PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES**

Power BI	Excel
SQL	DAX
M Query	Python
Javascript	

#### **EDUCATIONAL ATTAINMENT**

2014-2019 • Bachelor of Science in Accountancy

Mary the Queen College (MQC)

Jose Abad Santos Avenue, San Matias, Guagua, Pampanga

# TRAININGS, LICENSE, AND CERTIFICATIONS

Apr 2022 • Programming for Beginners Using Python

Mar 2022 • Build Python Web Apps with Flask

Mar 2022 • Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp

Sep 2021 • Statistical Analyses and Modelling Using SQL and Python

Oct 2019 • Certified Public Accountant

# **CHARACTER REFERENCE**

Contact No. 0939-910-7800

**Marc Quincy Talagtag** 

Diyan N. Axalan

Manager Colleague

Contact No. 0956-554-3113

I attest that all information contained in this resume is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

**RONEL B. MANLUTAC**